<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Sarim&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://sarimblog.vercel.app/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Sarim&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 Sarim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sarimblog.vercel.app/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Responsible AI: Navigating Bias and Fairness in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://sarimblog.vercel.app/posts/guide-to-responsible-ai--navigating-bias-and-fairness-in-large-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sarimblog.vercel.app/posts/guide-to-responsible-ai--navigating-bias-and-fairness-in-large-language-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;!&lt;img src=&#34;https://sarimblog.vercel.app/images/Pasted%20image%2020250925140300.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image Description&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs)—such as GPT-4, Llama, and Mistral—has revolutionized fields from generation to comprehension. Yet, with this incredible power comes a critical responsibility: ensuring these systems are fair and ethical. If you are looking to enter the world of AI development, understanding &lt;strong&gt;bias and fairness in LLMs&lt;/strong&gt; is your essential starting point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This growing field focuses on tackling the ethical and social risks of harm resulting from language models, the first category of which includes discrimination, hate speech, and exclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Every Developer Needs a Blog</title>
      <link>https://sarimblog.vercel.app/posts/why-every-developer-needs-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sarimblog.vercel.app/posts/why-every-developer-needs-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;!&lt;img src=&#34;https://sarimblog.vercel.app/images/Pasted%20image%2020250924225916.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image Description&#34;&gt;&#xA;In a world of portfolios and GitHub profiles, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to wonder if a personal blog is still relevant for developers. The answer is a resounding &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;. A blog is not just a place to share your thoughts; it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful tool that can significantly boost your personal growth and professional career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few reasons why you should start one today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-1-solidify-your-knowledge&#34;&gt;## 1. Solidify Your Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever tried to explain a complex topic to someone, only to realize you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand it as well as you thought? This is known as the &lt;strong&gt;Feynman Technique&lt;/strong&gt;. The act of writing down what you know forces you to confront the gaps in your understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
